<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <title>lenage博客</title>
 <link href="http://lenage.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://lenage.github.com/"/>
 <updated>2011-05-12T15:04:16+08:00</updated>
 <id>http://lenage.github.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>lenage</name>
   <email>lendage@gmail.com</email>
 </author>
 
   <entry>
     <title>github上的第一篇博客</title>
     <link href="http://lenage.github.com/2011/05/12/test/"/>
     <updated>2011-05-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
     <id>http://lenage.github.com/2011/05/12/test</id>
     <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;每次要到写博客的时候，突然发现一点都写不出来，生活中也没有什么好写的，当然这一篇完全是为了测试而写的。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;test&lt;/p&gt;</content>
   </entry>
 
   <entry>
     <title>开篇志</title>
     <link href="http://lenage.github.com/2011/05/12/first-blog/"/>
     <updated>2011-05-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
     <id>http://lenage.github.com/2011/05/12/first-blog</id>
     <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;灵感这东西不记录就没有了；生活也是，需要认真的记录。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;最近几天：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id='archlinux'&gt;上次archlinux升级中因没插电源中断之后重新安装，比以前好用多了；&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id='id1'&gt;经过重装后比上次好用多了；&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id='gnome3'&gt;昨天安装了gnome3，但是今天凌晨又卸载了，还是不喜欢厚重的感觉；&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id='openboxxcompmgr'&gt;现在使用openbox，动画效果用xcompmgr，阴影和淡入淡出效果还能接受；&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id='linux_flam3'&gt;分形图真的很美，在linux可以使用 flam3绘制；&lt;/h1&gt;</content>
   </entry>
 
   <entry>
     <title>Planning the Future of Antenna Mate</title>
     <link href="http://lenage.github.com/2011/05/11/planning-the-future-of-anrenna-nare/"/>
     <updated>2011-05-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
     <id>http://lenage.github.com/2011/05/11/planning-the-future-of-anrenna-nare</id>
     <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://antennamate.com'&gt;Antenna Mate&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; future is increased flexibility, more relevant data and availability in foreign markets. The app was originally conceptualised by &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/adrianfrost'&gt;Adrian Frost&lt;/a&gt; out of the frustration of aligning TV antennas and allocating channels in commercial MATV installations. Antenna Mate was designed around use cases that supported the nature of Adrian&amp;#8217;s work without considering user cases for other demographics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the beta it became apparent that caraveners and motorhome owners were equally as interested in Antenna Mate as professional installers. Both demographics share use cases. Where they diverge on is the emphasis to plan ahead versus more relevant data for making informed decisions. The difficulty in planning the future of Antenna Mate is continuing to satisfy both demographics without compromising the simplicity of the app. My default stance is to satisfy the majority with good defaults and minimise the amount of options. Options increase complexity and smell of a poorly thought out design. Balancing feature requests with code maintenance and a good user experience feels completely polarised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having read feature requests from users over and over, similarities begin to emerge and you start to understand what users really want even if they&amp;#8217;re unsure how to express it. Users make feature requests from the perspectives of their understanding/experience and respective demographic without any consideration for code maintenance or user experience. User feedback is critical, but it&amp;#8217;s important to carefully evaluate feature requests in a larger context. I value all of my users feedback. Their ideas ultimately seed bigger ideas to the benefit of everyone. As a result, I&amp;#8217;m pleased to list the following features that should satisfy a majority of the feature requests I&amp;#8217;ve received to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increase search radius to 150 km&lt;/strong&gt; from 100 km. 100 km is an arbitrary limit based on the assumption that users aren&amp;#8217;t interested in broadcasting sites far away (and performance constraints). Turns out I was wrong.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spectrum analyser&lt;/strong&gt; that lists the theoretical signal strength of each transmitter from your current location. Provides more relevant data for professional installers and is a dependancy for the next feature.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finding the strongest broadcasting&lt;/strong&gt; site as opposed to the closest broadcasting site. Distance isn&amp;#8217;t necessarily an indicator of the strongest broadcasting site when the transmitters are low powered. Suitable for users in regional areas who prefer major broadcasting sites instead of local, low powered retransmitters.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change current location to an arbitrary location&lt;/strong&gt;. You search for a location by city, town or suburb and Antenna Mate finds the strongest broadcasting site. This feature will depend on an internet connection for establishing the latitude and longitude of the desired location. In addition, it enables users to get around the 150 km limit.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universal app&lt;/strong&gt;. When you release an app on the App Store, Apple lists the devices the app is compatible with based on features the developer specifies as dependencies. Turns out the iPad Wifi+3G has a digital compass. Custom graphics and views will need to be created.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Availability in foreign markets&lt;/strong&gt;. The US and UK have a huge caraveners and motorhome demographic who could benefit from Antenna Mate. Moreover, Antenna Mate makes minimal use of the english language, preferring recognisable symbols. Such a design is the perfect candidate for internationalisation opening the possibility of entry into the European market. The biggest barrier to entry is legally attaining transmitter data and collaborating with local testers. Australian&amp;#8217;s are fortunate that the &lt;a href='http://www.acma.gov.au/WEB/STANDARD/pc=PC_9150'&gt;ACMA provides this data&lt;/a&gt; under a Creative Commons licence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content>
   </entry>
 
   <entry>
     <title>The Setup</title>
     <link href="http://lenage.github.com/2011/04/16/the-setup/"/>
     <updated>2011-04-16T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
     <id>http://lenage.github.com/2011/04/16/the-setup</id>
     <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href='http://usesthis.com/'&gt;The Setup&lt;/a&gt;, I thought I&amp;#8217;d share mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/tatejohnson/5604528053/in/set-72157623446355659/lightbox/'&gt;&lt;img alt='Workstation and desk' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5308/5604528053_b4350764af_d.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My setup at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='hardware'&gt;Hardware&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href='http://www.apple.com/macbookpro/'&gt;15&amp;#8221; MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; is my choice of computer for its power and portability. Although a majority of my time spent on the computer is at a desk, the flexibility to move between work, meetings and home is critical. It features a 2.66GHz Core i7, 8GB RAM and a 240GB SSD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At home and work I plug into a &lt;a href='http://www.apple.com/displays/'&gt;27&amp;#8221; LED Cinema Display&lt;/a&gt;. The resolution, sharpness and colours from this display are the best I&amp;#8217;ve ever seen. Having a large display enhances my workflow by being able to fit my terminal, text editor and web browser side-by-side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All my input devices are wireless. I prefer wireless for minimising clutter. I have a &lt;a href='http://www.apple.com/keyboard/'&gt;Wireless Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://www.apple.com/magicmouse/'&gt;Magic Mouse&lt;/a&gt;. Touch based scrolling feels great and never needs cleaning. My &lt;a href='http://www.apple.com/battery-charger/'&gt;Apple Battery Charger&lt;/a&gt; means I never need to need to worry about running out of batteries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='software'&gt;Software&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I switched to &lt;a href='http://www.apple.com/macosx/'&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; in 2007 after using &lt;a href='http://www.gentoo.org/'&gt;various&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='http://www.ubuntu.com/'&gt;flavours&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href='http://www.archlinux.org/'&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; for a couple of years. I really like the healthy amount of excellent open source and propriety software living side-by-side on the Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether I am writing a blog post, writing code or administrating a server I&amp;#8217;ll have at least one &lt;a href='http://www.apple.com/macosx/what-is-macosx/apps-and-utilities.html#terminal'&gt;Terminal&lt;/a&gt; window open. I use &lt;a href='http://git-scm.com/'&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; for versioning control and a fork of &lt;a href='https://github.com/brotherbard/gitx'&gt;GitX&lt;/a&gt; as a commit browser. Package management is delegated to &lt;a href='http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/'&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;. Homebrew&amp;#8217;s simplicity and visibility on GitHub is its greatest attraction over alternative package managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Development happens primarily in &lt;a href='http://macromates.com/'&gt;TextMate&lt;/a&gt;. I say primarily because I use TextMate for everything except Cocoa/Objective-C. I&amp;#8217;m aware of everyone&amp;#8217;s desire to migrate to an editor that&amp;#8217;s more actively developed, but I&amp;#8217;m content with TextMate. Even after all these years, it has a diverse plugin ecosystem that continues to thrive. For Cocoa/Objective-C development I use none other than &lt;a href='http://developer.apple.com/tools/xcode/'&gt;Xcode&lt;/a&gt;. I browse MySQL databases with &lt;a href='http://www.sequelpro.com/'&gt;Sequel Pro&lt;/a&gt; and SQLite databases with &lt;a href='http://menial.co.uk/software/base/'&gt;Base&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href='http://ditchnet.org/httpclient/'&gt;HTTP Client&lt;/a&gt; is a nice, native alternative to curl and &lt;a href='http://www.tuffcode.com/'&gt;HTTP Scoop&lt;/a&gt; is immensely useful for sniffing HTTP requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of using Firefox and a short stint with Safari, I&amp;#8217;ve settled on &lt;a href='http://www.google.com/chrome'&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt; as my primary web browser. For me, Chrome represents what Firefox originally represented. Minimal, fast, innovative and continually updated. Webkit Inspector is mature enough that I no longer crawl back to Firebug for debugging. I tweet with &lt;a href='http://www.echofon.com/twitter/mac'&gt;Echofon for Mac&lt;/a&gt;, instant message with &lt;a href='http://adium.im/'&gt;Adium&lt;/a&gt; and chat with &lt;a href='http://colloquy.info/'&gt;Colloquy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://agilewebsolutions.com/onepassword'&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt; has had the biggest impact on my workflow in the last six months. I have accounts on numerous websites and services as well as passwords for dozens of servers and systems at work. Not having to remember all these passwords in combination with browser integration means I can save my memory for things that matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do all my note taking with &lt;a href='http://notational.net/'&gt;Notational Velocity&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s fast, plain text and searchable. Brainstorming, diagrams and iOS UI mocks are best done in &lt;a href='http://www.omnigroup.com/products/omnigraffle/'&gt;OmniGraffle&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href='http://www.alfredapp.com/'&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt; is an alternative to Spotlight that lets you switch tracks in iTunes by typing the name of the track or artist. &lt;a href='http://www.telestream.net/screen-flow/overview.htm'&gt;ScreenFlow&lt;/a&gt; is great for recording screencasts. At the end of an iteration at work, we present a demo to the business and record it as a screencast which we share with our colleagues in other cities. &lt;a href='http://www.vmware.com/products/fusion/overview.html'&gt;VMWare Fusion&lt;/a&gt; lets me keep Windows for IE testing and to try out new flavours of Linux every now and then. I still design, mock and touch up in &lt;a href='http://www.adobe.com/products/photoshop.html?promoid=DTELR'&gt;Photoshop CS5&lt;/a&gt; and use &lt;a href='http://www.getcloudapp.com/'&gt;Cloud App&lt;/a&gt; for quickly sharing images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='dream_setup'&gt;Dream Setup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lugging around a 15&amp;#8221; laptop is tolerable, but would benefit immensely from a smaller laptop. At the time I bought the this Macbook Pro the Core i7 processors were not available in the 13&amp;#8221; model. Ideally, I&amp;#8217;d like something like the Macbook Air with more RAM and a faster processor. Couldn&amp;#8217;t care less about the &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/tatejohnson/status/30519424754647041'&gt;optical drive&lt;/a&gt; or ethernet. I already have a large display at home and work so portability is more valuable to me.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
   </entry>
 
</feed>
